Chuck Chau

(626) 233-1319 ★ cchau2@gmail.com ★ https://www.linkedin.com/in/cchau2 ★ https://github.com/volkstrader/resume

Dedicated and versatile software development professional with experience in architecting, planning, coaching, and delivering innovative technology solutions. Demonstrated ability establishing iterative process to set short and long-term IT strategic plan; leading full cycle development to ensure on-time, on-target completion

- Interpreting stakeholders needs into user stories and acceptance criteria
- Giving technical advice to management team
- Prototyping architecture framework solution
- Writing technical documentation and user guides
- Coaching technical staffs on new technologies and processes
- Coordinating internal and external technology resources to realize deliverables

Core Competencies

- Software System Architecture
- IT Strategic Planning
- Microservices

- Continuous Integration (CI) Automation
- Application Lifecycle Management
- Serverless Design and Implementation

Design Principles

- Customer / User Oriented
- Workflow Decoupling
- Separation of Concern
- Dependency Inversion
- Single Point of Truth

- Convention over Configuration
- Standard over Proprietary
- KISS Keep It Small and Simple
- MVP Minimum Viable Product
- DRY Don't Repeat Yourself

Technical Proficiencies

| Platforms | Windows, Linux, AWS, Docker, Team Foundation Server 2017 (TFS), Confluence, Jira, Salesforce |
|--------------------|--|
| | .Net C# (.Net dotnetcore, .Net Standard), Meta-programming, Reflection, |
| Programming | Managed Extensibility Framework (MEF), Autofac |
| Frameworks | <i>javascript</i> node.js, RxJs, AngularJS, Data-Driven-Document (D3) |
| | UML, Python, Powershell, Bash, T-SQL, GoLang, Salesforce-Apex |
| Databases | MS SQL Server, MySQL, DynamoDb, Redis, ElasticSearch, Couchbase, |
| | MongoDb, PostgreSQL |
| AWS Services | API Gateway, Beanstalk, Cognito, DynamoDb, EC2, IAM, Lambda, RDS, KMS, S3, |
| | SNS, SQS |
| Services | Redgate SQLClone, Redgate SQL Automation with Powershell, SVG, Google |
| | DoubleClick for Publisher (DFP), Google Analytic (Universal Analytic), Google |
| Packages | Tag Manager (GTM), Twilio |

Employment History

| Associate Director, Software Architecture, IT Development Commitee, ETC Processing | 12/2016- 12/2017 |
|--|------------------|
| Technologies LLC, Los Angeles, CA, | |
| Senior Software Engineer, CoStar Group, Ontario, CA, | 4/2011- 12/2016 |
| Technical Lead/Architect, Marshall & Swift/Boeckh (MSB), Los Angeles, CA, | 7/2010- 4/2011 |
| Senior Software Engineer, Green Dot Corporation (GDC), Morovia, CA, | 4/2008- 7/2010 |
| Senior Software Engineer, Marshall & Swift/Boeckh (MSB), Los Angeles, CA, | 4/2004- 4/2008 |
| Software Engineer, Prospect Science and Technology (PST), Rosemead, CA, | 9/1998- 3/2003 |

1/2/2018 Chuck Chau Resume

Recent Professional Experiences

Associate Director, Software Architecture, IT Development Committee ETC Processing

Technologies LLC, Los Angeles, CA

Client API on AWS API Gateway

Client API will allow ETC to pursue new line of security clearing business from online brokers, and integrate their trading platforms with ETC back office

Continuous Integration (CI) Implementation

Defined and applied new Application Lifecycle Management process to development team (dev team), using Team Foundation Server 2017

IT Strategic Planning / Roadmap

CEO appointed to lead the effort to create IT Strategic Plan and Roadmap process

Kafka / CoreOS

Creating a prototype to convert real time trading/settlement data coming from multiple sources into Kafka data stream

System Architecture Assessment

Documented the current system architecture and proposed a NextGen vision

Tooling Assessment / Recommendation

Identified and recommended new tooling software in the area of Team Communication, Project Management, Application Lifecycle Management, and Development

Senior Software Engineer CoStar Group, Ontario, CA

Enterprise Ecommerce Pricing Engine / Service

Designed and implemented an enterprise solution for calculating shopping cart and generating price sheet, with multi-dimentional price plan and discount schema

Marketplace Ad Creative Publishing 2.0

Acted in the role of technical lead to refactor ad creative editing workflow, utilized technologies, such as SVG, D3, Akamai, browser canvas

Ecommerce tracking using Google Universal Analytics (UA) with Google Tag Manager (GTM)

Designed and implemented an integrated solution to track e-commerce activities on

LoopNet.com website using GA via GTM

Marketplace Ad System integrate with Google DFP

Designed and implemented an ad platform, integrated with Google DFP, for selling ad spaces on LoopNet.com

Cityfeet.com and Loopnet.com Google Universal Analytic (UA)

Designed and implemented a solution to track user behavioral data, such as clicks, social sharing, using Google Universal Analytic (UA)

Cityfeet.com Enhancements

Upgrade UI framework and improve SEO results for cityfeet.com

Recognitions

Nominated CoStar Innovation Award
CoSart Developer Conference
Winner of CosStar Innovation Challenge
CoStar Developer Conference
2012

Education

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona 1998
B.S. Computer Science